Guide to the Robert Moses Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Inventory, 1934-(1952-1970)
  - 1962: 3rd volume
    - SPEECHES AND RELEASES: 1962
      - BUCKLEY, THE HON. CHAS. A. (Box 4)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT DINNER MAY 21.
      - "BUSES CAN NOT BE PERMITTED ON PARKWAYS" (Box 4)
        STATEMENT BY R.M. APRIL 22.
      - BUSES ON THE PARKWAYS (Box 4)
        REPLY OF R.M. TO MR. JOHN A. MILLER AND OTHERS MAY 9.
      - CITIZENS' ACTION COMMISSION (Box 4)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT MEETING "TOWN, GOWN AND THE NEW NEW HAVEN" NEW HAVEN, CONN. FEBRUARY 28.
      - FORDHAM UNIVERSITY SCHOOL OF BUSINESS (Box 4)
        REMARKS BY R.M. ON MANAGEMENT AT DINNER DECEMBER 1.
      - GENERAL MOTORS BREAKFAST (Box 4)
        REMARKS OF R.M. MAY 8.
      - "HALF WAY TO THE FAIR" (Box 4)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT UNIVERSITY CLUB MARCH 10.
      - LAKE WELCH BEACH (Box 4)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT OPENING PALISADES INTERSTATE PARK JUNE 15.
      - LATIN AMERICAN LUNCHEON (Box 4)
        REMARKS OF R.M. WASHINGTON, D. C. JULY 16.
      - LONG ISLAND EXPRESSWAY (Box 4)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT OPENING OF ANOTHER SECTION AUGUST 15.
      - LYONS, JAMES J. (Box 4)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT THE CITIZENS' DINNER JANUARY 25.
      - MITCHEL FIELD, FUTURE OF (Box 4)
        STATEMENT BY R.M. AT FEDERAL AVIATION AGENCY HEARING JANUARY 16.
      - NEW YORK MIRROR YOUTH PROGRAM (Box 4)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT HUMANITARIAN AWARD DINNER OCTOBER 28.
      - NORTH GRAND ISLAND BRIDGE (Box 4)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT GROUNDBREAKING CEREMONY AT SITE OCTOBER 11.
      - NATIONAL HIGHWAY USERS CONFERENCE (Box 4)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT LUNCHEON MAYFLOWER HOTEL, WASHINGTON, D. C. "THE OPEN ROAD" MAY 9.
      - PENN STATION SOUTH (Box 4)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT DEDICATION MAY 19.
      - PHILHARMONIC HALL AT LINCOLN CENTER (Box 4)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT OPENING ABC RADIO TAPING SEPTEMBER 23.
      - "POST AND PRE-ELECTION REFLECTIONS" (Box 4)
        AN INFORMAL TALK BY R.M. OVERSEAS PRESS CLUB NOVEMBER 29.
      - "PUT IT IN ENGLISH" (Box 4)
        TALK BY R.M. TO THIRD AND FOURTH CLASSES OF UNITED STATES MILITARY ACADEMY WEST POINT JANUARY 23.
      - QUEENS. COLLEGE, TWENTY--FIFTH ANNIVERSARY (Box 4)
        REMARKS OF R.M. OCTOBER 26.
      - REGIONAL GROWTH (Box 4)
        REMARKS BY R.M. AT ANNUAL DINNER OF THE SAN FRANCISCO BAY AREA COUNCIL SAN FRANCISCO, CALIFORNIA APRIL 26.
      - REGIONAL TRANSPORTATION ADVISORY BOARD (Box 4)
        "FROM L'ENFANT TO THE MOTOR AGE" MARRIOTT MOTOR HOTEL, ARLINGTON, VA. SEPTEMBER 25.
      - RODGERS, RICHARD (Box 4)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT LUNCHEON ON OCCASION OF HIS SIXTIETH BIRTHDAY JUNE 28.
      - SARATOGA SPRINGS (Box 4)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT OPENING OF PARK AND RECREATION AREA JUNE 30.
      - SEATTLE FAIR (Box 4)
        STATEMENT OF R.M. AT OPENING APRIL 21.
      - SKIDMORE, LOUIS (Box 4)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT MEMORIAL SERVICES OCTOBER 24.
      - SOLDIERS AND SAILORS MONUMENT (Box 4)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT REDEDICATION RIVERSIDE PARK NOVEMBER 11.
      - SULLIVAN, ED (Box 4)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT DINNER OF CHAMPIONS OCTOBER 16.
      - WAGNER, ROBERT F. (Box 4)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT STATE DINNER JANUARY 30.
      - ZECKENDORF, WILLIAM (Box 4)
        REMARKS OF R.M. AT EIGHTH ANNIVERSARY BALL, C.W. POST COLLEGE, L.I.U., BROOKVILLE, N. Y. NOVEMBER 3.
  - 1962: 4th volume
    - BOOKS--MISCELLANEOUS
      - PALISADES INTERSTATE PARK COMMISSION LAKE WELCH BEACH, JUNE 15, 1962. (Box 4)
      - JONES BEACH STATE PARK--FIRE ISLAND STATE PARK--PROGRESS REPORT, JUNE 25, 1962. (Box 4)
      - THE ABANDONMENT OF MITCHEL FIELD AS AN AIR FORCE BASE AND ITS CONVERSION TO THE BEST COMMUNITY USE, JULY 2, 1962. (Box 4)
      - THE PROTECTION AND PRESERVATION OF THE ATLANTIC SHORE FRONT OF THE STATE OF NEW YORK--FINAL REPORT, JULY 27, 1962. (Box 4)
      - ANNOUNCEMENT OF PRESERVATION OF TWO LARGE FISH AND GAME CLUBS ON LONG ISLAND, JULY 30, 1962. (Box 4)
      - $25,000,000 SUPPLEMENTAL BOND ISSUE, OCTOBER 15, 1962. (Box 4)
      - HECKSCHER STATE PARKWAY AND PARK IMPROVEMENTS, NOVEMBER 3, 1962. (Box 4)
      - HARTFORD PAVILION IN CENTRAL PARK, MARCH 12, 1962. (Box 4)
      - MANHATTAN BEACH WATERFRONT PARK ADDITION, MAY 1, 1962. (Box 4)
      - SHORE FRONT DRIVE--BOROUGH OF RICHMOND, JULY 23, 1962. (Box 4)
    - MAGAZINES AND NEWSPAPER ARTICLES
      - THE ATLANTIC MONTHLY: ARE CITIES DEAD?, JANUARY 1962 ISSUE. (Box 4)
      - LONG ISLAND PRESS: PUT IT IN ENGLISH!, JANUARY 27, 1962. (Box 4)
      - NEW YORK JOURNAL AMERICAN: BOB MOSES LOOKS AHEAD., JANUARY 28, 1962. (Box 4)
      - SHOW: SEAN O'CASEY., FEBRUARY 1962 ISSUE. (Box 4)
      - NEW YORK TIMES SUNDAY MAGAZINE: PLEA: 'PUT IT IN ENGLISH.', MARCH 4, 1962. (Box 4)
      - LONG ISLAND SUNDAY PRESS: HELL AND HIGH WATER--THE PROBLEM OF NEW YORK'S ATLANTIC SHORE., MARCH 25, 1962. (Box 4)
      - LONG ISLAND SUNDAY PRESS (REPRINT): HELL AND HIGH WATER--THE PROBLEM OF NEW YORK'S ATLANTIC SHORE., MARCH 25, 1962. (Box 4)
      - LONG ISLAND PRESS: THE BATTLES OF THE BEACHES., JULY 8, 1962. (Box 4)
      - SHOW: ROBERT MOSES AUTHOR., AUGUST 1962 ISSUE. (Box 4)
      - THE NEW YORK TIMES MAGAZINE: MOSES MEETS THE PRESS--HEAD ON., AUGUST 5, 1962. (Box 4)
      - LIFE: DISPUTATIOUS DIRT-MOVER., OCTOBER 5, 1962. (Box 4)
      - UNITED PRESS INTERNATIONAL--WORLD HORIZONS: MULTI-MAN MOSES., DECEMBER 16, 1962. (Box 4)
  - 1963: 1st volume
    - MAGAZINE ARTICLES: 1963
      - 1. AMERICAN ENGINEER--"ENGINEERING SETS THE STAGE FOR THE NEW YORK WORLD'S FAIR", SEPTEMBER 1963 (Box 4A)
      - 2. ARCHITECTURAL FORUM--"EXHIBITION ARCHITECTURE", AUGUST 1963 (Box 4A)
      - 3. BUSINESS SCREEN MAGAZINE--"NEW YORK WORLD'S FAIR REPORT" --1963 (Box 4A)
      - 4. CONSTRUCTION CRAFTSMAN--"CONSTRUCTION AT THE NEW YORK WORLD'S FAIR", SEPTEMBER 1963 (Box 4A)
      - 5. CONTRACTORS AND ENGINEERS--"SPECTACULAR SHAPES RISE AT WORLD'S FAIR", JULY 1963 (Box 4A)
      - 6. ENGINEERING NEWS RECORD--"WORLD'S FAIR: THE PIECES TAKE SHAPE", OCTOBER 31 (Box 4A)
      - 7. EQUINEWS--"GOING TO THE FAIR", JULY 1963 (Box 4A)
      - 8. LONG ISLAND MAGAZINE--"LESS THAN ONE YEAR TO GO!", JUNE-JULY 1963 (Box 4A)
      - 9. LOOK MAGAZINE--"NEW YORK'S MIGHTY MOSES", MARCH 26 (Box 4A)
      - 10. LOOK MAGAZINE--"A FAIR TAKES SHAPE", NOVEMBER 19 (Box 4A)
      - 11. NEW YORKER--"ONWARD AND UPWARD WITH THE ARTS--DIPLOMACY AT FLUSHING MEADOW", JUNE 1 (Box 4A)
      - 12. ROCKAWAY REVIEW--"PICTURE PREVIEW OF THE WORLD'S FAIR", AUGUST-SEPTEMBER 1963 (Box 4A)
      - 13. THINK MAGAZINE--"WORLD'S FAIR PREVIEW", OCTOBER 1963 (Box 4A)
      - 14. TIME--"THE FAIR--PROGRESS REPORT", FEBRUARY 8. (Box 4A)
      - 15. WORLD POWER DIGEST--"WORLD'S FAIR"--1963 (Box 4A)
    - NEWSPAPER ARTICLES: 1963
      - 1. BABYLON EAGLE, THE--"RICHLY DESERVED ACCOLADE", JULY 4 (Box 4A)
      - 2. CHATTANOOGA TIMES, THE--"MOSES AND METRO", FEBRUARY 5 (Box 4A)
      - 3. DAILY NEWS, NEW YORK: "THE SUPREME COURT"--ROBERT MOSES COMMENT ON PRAYERS IN SCHOOLS, JUNE 9 (Box 4A)
      - 4. DAILY NEWS, NEW YORK: "AT 75, BOB MOSES STILL SEEKS BIGGER CHALLENGE", DECEMBER 18 (Box 4A)
      - 5. DAILY PRESS, LONG ISLAND--"EVEN 'MOSES PARK' FAILS TO AWE BOB", SEPTEMBER 18 (Box 4A)
      - 6. HERALD TRIBUNE, NEW YORK: "BOOK OF MOSES" BY RED SMITH, JUNE 13 (Box 4A)
      - 7. HERALD TRIBUNE, NEW YORK: "TOP OF THE WORLD", SEPTEMBER 29 (Box 4A)
      - 8. HERALD TRIBUNE, NEW YORK: "75--THE MAN OF MANY JOUSTS AND MANY JOBS", DECEMBER 15 (Box 4A)
      - 9. JOURNAL AMERICAN, NEW YORK: "AMAZING MR. MOSES", JULY 6 (Box 4A)
      - 10. JOURNAL AMERICAN, NEW YORK: "FAIR CHANCE FOR AMERICA-WORLD'S FAIR", NOVEMBER 21 (Box 4A)
      - 11. OGDENBURG JOURNAL, THE: "ROBERT MOSES ON THE ST. LAWRENCE", JULY 5 (Box 4A)
      - 12. OGDENBURG JOURNAL, THE: "MOSES WILL ATTEND MASSENA DEDICATION OF PARK IN HIS HONOR", JULY 5 (Box 4A)
      - 13. OREGONIAN THE SUNDAY - "MOSES REPORT ON FUTURE OF [illegible] (Box 4A)
      - 14. POST, LONG ISLAND--"MOSES & THE PRESS", OCTOBER 17 (Box 4A)
      - 15. REGISTER, THE NEW HAVEN--"ROBERT MOSES--NOW HE'LL SHOW THE WORLD!", AUGUST 4 (Box 4A)
      - 16. TIMES, THE NEW YORK: "WORLD'S FAIR PREVIEW", OCTOBER 6 (Box 4A)
      - 17. TIMES, THE NEW YORK: "VISIT U.S.A.--WORLD'S FAIR PREVIEW"--INTERNATIONAL EDITION, DECEMBER 5 (Box 4A)
      - 18. TIMES, THE NEW YORK: "A MASTER BUILDER IS 75", DECEMBER 15 (Box 4A)
      - 19. TIMES, THE NEW YORK: "MR. MOSES AT 75", DECEMBER 18 (Box 4A)
      - 20. WORLD-TELEGRAM AND SUN, NEW YORK: "JOB CHALLENGE TO MOSES--MASTER BUILDER", OCTOBER 21 (Box 4A)
      - 21. WORLD-TELEGRAM AND SUN, NEW YORK: "MAGIC IN THE MAKING"--SPECIAL WORLD'S FAIR EDITION, OCTOBER 2[illegible] (Box 4A)
      - 22. WORLD-TELEGRAM AND SUN, NEW YORK: "MAKE IT A WONDERFUL FAIR", NOVEMBER 18 (Box 4A)
    - RELEASES--NEW YORK WORLD'S FAIR 1964-1965 CORP.: 1963
      - FREE OR REDUCED RATES FOR SCHOOL CHILDREN
        - 1. REMARKS OF ROBERT MOSES, OCTOBER 2 (Box 4A)
        - 2. STATEMENT BY ROBERT MOSES, OCTOBER 4 (Box 4A)
        - 3. STATEMENT OF THE EXECUTIVE COMMITTEE, OCTOBER 16 (Box 4A)
        - 4. (2) STATEMENTS BY ROBERT MOSES, OCTOBER 23 (Box 4A)
        - 5. LETTER FROM ARTHUR H. MOTLEY, OCTOBER 31 (Box 4A)
        - 6. STATEMENT BY ROBERT MOSES, NOVEMBER 4 (Box 4A)
        - 7. JOINT STATEMENT BY MAYOR WAGNER & ROBERT MOSES, DECEMBER 3 (Box 4A)
      - ART AT THE FAIR
        - 1. STATEMENT BY ROBERT MOSES, NOVEMBER 18 (Box 4A)
        - 2. LETTER TO THE EDITOR, N. Y. TIMES, JUDGE ROSENMAN, NOVEMBER 18 (Box 4A)
      - POPE JOHN XXIII, DEATH OF
        - 1. STATEMENT BY ROBERT MOSES, JUNE 3 (Box 4A)
      - HALL OF SCIENCE
        - 1. STATEMENT BY ROBERT MOSES, OCTOBER 7 (Box 4A)
      - MISC. PRESS CLIPPINGS
        - 1. VOLUME 1, NUMBER 2, MAY 10 (Box 4A)
        - 2. VOLUME 1, NUMBER 4, JUNE 28 (Box 4A)
  - 1963: 2nd volume
    - TRIBOROUGH BRIDGE AND TUNNEL AUTHORITY: 1963
      - 1. DIRECTORY AND MAP--NEW YORK--NEW JERSEY, 1963 (Box 4A)
      - 2. CROSS-BRONX EXPRESSWAY, ALEXANDER HAMILTON BRIDGE, GEORGE WASHINGTON BRIDGE BUS STATION, OPENING OF, 1/17 (Box 4A)
      - 3. VERRAZANO-NARROWS BRIDGE--CABLE SPINNING, 3/7 (Box 4A)
      - 4. STATEMENT BY ROBERT MOSES IN OPPOSITION TO THE REMOVAL OF THE LOWER MANHATTAN EXPRESSWAY FROM THE CITY MAP, 4/17 (Box 4A)
      - 5. ARTERIAL PROGRESS, 5/13 (Box 4A)
      - 6. FUTURE ARTERIAL PROGRAM, 6/10 (Box 4A)
      - 7. ANNUAL REPORT, 1963 (Box 4A)
    - MISCELLANEOUS: 1963
      - 1. NIAGARA POWER PAMPHLET--POWER AUTHORITY OF THE STATE OF NEW YORK, 1963 (Box 4A)
      - 2. PROPOSED DEPARTMENT OF PARKS RECREATION CENTER--NEW YORK BOULEVARD AT 134TH STREET, 2/18 (Box 4A)
      - 3. POWER AUTHORITY OF THE STATE OF NEW YORK--8 YEARS OF PERFORMANCE--ANNUAL REPORT, 2/25 (Box 4A)
      - 4. RESOLUTION OF FINGER LAKES STATE PARKS COMMISSIONERS IN APPRECIATION OF PUBLIC SERVICE OF ROBERT MOSES, 4/18 (Box 4A)
      - 5. POWER VISTA--AT THE ROBERT MOSES NIAGARA POWER PLANT, DEDICATION OF, 7/19 (Box 4A)
      - 6. CONSULTING ENGINEERS, AMERICAN INSTITUTE OF--DINNER AT AMERICANA HOTEL--PROGRAM, 10/29 (Box 4A)
  - 1963: 3rd volume
    - REPORTS--NEW YORK WORLD'S FAIR: 1963
      - 1. FAIR NEWS, JANUARY 21 (Box 4A)
      - 2. FAIR NEWS, FEBRUARY 19 (Box 4A)
      - 3. FAIR NEWS, MARCH 6 (Box 4A)
      - 4. FAIR NEWS, APRIL 16 (Box 4A)
      - 5. FAIR NEWS, MAY 4 (Box 4A)
      - 6. FAIR NEWS, JUNE 17 (Box 4A)
      - 7. FAIR NEWS, JULY 22 (Box 4A)
      - 8. FAIR NEWS, LABOR DAY (Box 4A)
      - 9. FAIR NEWS, OCTOBER 29 (Box 4A)
      - 10. FAIR NEWS, NOVEMBER 22 (Box 4A)
      - 11. FAIR NEWS, HOLIDAY ISSUE (Box 4A)
      - 12. PROGRESS REPORT #7, JANUARY 24 (Box 4A)
      - 13. PROGRESS REPORT #8, APRIL 22 (Box 4A)
      - 14. PROGRESS REPORT #9, SEPTEMBER 26 (Box 4A)
      - 15. INDUSTRIAL SECTION (Box 4A)
      - 16. WORLD'S FAIR MARINA--LAUNCHING OF FIRST UNIT, JANUARY 23 (Box 4A)
      - 17. THE ECONOMIC BENEFITS OF THE NEW YORK WORLD'S FAIR (Box 4A)
      - 18. GRAPHIC STANDARDS MANUAL (Box 4A)
      - 19. MODEL ROOM--NEW YORK WORLD'S FAIR 1964-1965 (Box 4A)
      - 20. WORLD'S FAIR BROCHURE (Box 4A)
      - 21. OFFICIAL TICKET INFORMATION--2 (Box 4A)
      - 22. OFFICIAL PREVIEW--HUNTLEY-BRINKLEY REPORT ON THE FAIR (Box 4A)
  - 1963: 4th volume
    - GROUNDBREAKINGS--NEW YORK WORLD'S FAIR: 1963
      - 1. INDONESIA, THE PAVILION OF, JANUARY 18 (Box 4A)
      - 2. WORLD OF FOOD PAVILION, JANUARY 23 (Box 4A)
      - 3. FRENCH PAVILION, FEBRUARY 5 (Box 4A)
      - 4. BETTER LIVING BUILDING, FEBRUARY 13 (Box 4A)
      - 5. EDUCATION, THE HALL OF, FEBRUARY 14 (Box 4A)
      - 6. FIRST NATIONAL CITY BANK, FEBRUARY 26 (Box 4A)
      - 7. SWISS PAVILION, MARCH 1 (Box 4A)
      - 8. SWEDISH PAVILION, MARCH 21 (Box 4A)
      - 9. CHURCH OF JESUS CHRIST OF LATTER-DAY SAINTS, THE, MARCH 27 (Box 4A)
      - 10. CENTRAL AMERICA PAVILION, MARCH 28 (Box 4A)
      - 11. VENEZUELA PAVILION, MARCH 29 (Box 4A)
      - 12. INDIA, PAVILION OF, APRIL 8 (Box 4A)
      - 13. SIERRA LEONE, APRIL 10 (Box 4A)
      - 14. BEAUTIFUL BELGIAN VILLAGE, APRIL 11 (Box 4A)
      - 15. UNITED STATES POST OFFICE, APRIL 15 (Box 4A)
      - 16. BILLY GRAHAM PAVILION, THE, APRIL 17 (Box 4A)
      - 17. PAKISTAN PAVILION, APRIL 18 (Box 4A)
      - 18. CHRISTIAN SCIENCE PAVILION, APRIL 21 (Box 4A)
      - 19. MINNESOTA PAVILION, THE, APRIL 22 (Box 4A)
      - 20. PHILIPPINE PAVILION, THE, APRIL 24 (Box 4A)
      - 21. SCHAEFER CENTER, APRIL 25 (Box 4A)
      - 22. AUSTRIAN PAVILION, APRIL 26 (Box 4A)
      - 23. WEST VIRGINIA PAVILION, THE, APRIL 29 (Box 4A)
      - 24. INTERNATIONAL PLAZA, MAY 2 (Box 4A)
      - 25. HALL OF FREE ENTERPRISE, MAY 8 (Box 4A)
      - 26. CONTINENTAL INSURANCE COMPANIES, MAY 10 (Box 4A)
      - 27. MALAYA, PAVILION OF THE FEDERATION OF, MAY 13 (Box 4A)
      - 28. GENERAL CIGAR CO., INC., MAY 13 (Box 4A)
      - 29. SEVEN-UP EXHIBIT, THE, MAY 15 (Box 4A)
      - 30. CENTURY GRILL, MAY 17 (Box 4A)
      - 31. MISSOURI PAVILION, MAY 24 (Box 4A)
      - 32. NEW JERSEY TERCENTENARY PAVILION, MAY 27 (Box 4A)
      - 33. WESTINGHOUSE TIME CAPSULE, JUNE 14 (Box 4A)
      - 34. SPAIN, PAVILION OF, JUNE 18 (Box 4A)
      - 35. MUSEUM OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY, THE NEW YORK CITY, JUNE 19 (Box 4A)
      - 36. SUDAN, PAVILION OF THE REPUBLIC OF, JUNE 27 (Box 4A)
      - 37. JORDAN, PAVILION OF THE HASHEMITE KINGDOM OF, JULY 2 (Box 4A)
      - 38. GUINEA, THE PAVILION OF THE REPUBLIC OF, JULY 18 (Box 4A)
      - 39. KOREA, PAVILION OF THE REPUBLIC OF, JULY 23 (Box 4A)
      - 40. MOROCCO, THE PAVILION OF, JULY 25 (Box 4A)
      - 41. SERMONS FROM SCIENCE, AUGUST 1 (Box 4A)
      - 42. LEBANON, THE PAVILION OF, AUGUST 15 (Box 4A)
      - 43. NEW ENGLAND STATES, THE PAVILION OF THE, SEPTEMBER 19 (Box 4A)
      - 44. GREECE, PAVILION OF, SEPTEMBER 25 (Box 4A)
    - OTHER CEREMONIES--NEW YORK WORLD'S FAIR: 1963
      - 1. UNITED STATES STEEL UNISPHERE CEREMONIES, MARCH 6 (Box 4A)
      - 2. HONG KONG ROOF RAISING CEREMONIES, MARCH 14 (Box 4A)
      - 3. COCA-COLA COMPANY PAVILION, MAY 7 (Box 4A)
      - 4. GENERAL DOUGLAS MacARTHUR VISITS THE NEW YORK WORLD'S FAIR, MAY 9 (Box 4A)
      - 5. FLORIDA CITRUS TOWER, DEDICATION OF THE, JUNE 24 (Box 4A)
      - 6. IRELAND COMMEMORATION STONE CEREMONY, JUNE 28 (Box 4A)
      - 7. MASONIC BROTHERHOOD CENTER, START OF CONSTRUCTION CEREMONIES, AUGUST 20 (Box 4A)
      - 8. ARGENTINA, PAVILION OF, CORNERSTONE LAYING CEREMONY, SEPTEMBER 11 (Box 4A)
      - 9. OKLAHOMA, THE PAVILION OF--TREE PLANTING CEREMONY, SEPTEMBER 16 (Box 4A)
      - 10. UNITED ARAB REPUBLIC, PAVILION OF THE--FOUNDATION LAYING CEREMONY, SEPTEMBER 19 (Box 4A)
      - 11. MEXICO, THE PAVILION OF THE UNITED STATES OF--CORNERSTONE LAYING CEREMONY, SEPTEMBER 19 (Box 4A)
      - 12. DENMARK, THE PAVILION OF, FLAG RAISING CEREMONY (Box 4A)
      - 13. WAX MUSEUM, WALTER'S INTERNATIONAL--DEDICATION, OCTOBER 1 (Box 4A)
      - 14. LOUISIANA, THE PAVILION OF--DEDICATION CEREMONIES, OCTOBER 10 (Box 4A)
      - 15. AMERICAN EXPRESS--WORLD PRESS ANNOUNCEMENT CEREMONY, OCTOBER 11 (Box 4A)
      - 16. AMERICAN-ISRAEL PAVILION--DEDICATION CEREMONY, OCTOBER 14 (Box 4A)
      - 17. PORT AUTHORITY HELIPORT OPENING CEREMONY, OCTOBER 16 (Box 4A)
      - 18. AUTO THRILL SHOW--PREVIEW, OCTOBER 30 (Box 4A)
      - 19. SCOUTING, THE WONDERFUL WORLD OF--START OF CONSTRUCTION, NOVEMBER 12 (Box 4A)
      - 20. AFRICA, THE PAVILION OF--PRESS CONFERENCE, NOVEMBER 12 (Box 4A)
      - 21. AVIS ANTIQUE RENT A CAR--DEDICATION DAY, NOVEMBER 18 (Box 4A)
  - 1963: 5th volume
    - SPEECHES BY ROBERT MOSES: 1963
      - 1. ALEXANDER HAMILTON BRIDGE, GEORGE WASHINGTON BRIDGE BUS STATION, SECTIONS OF CROSS-BRONX EXPRESSWAY, OPENING OF, JANUARY 17 (Box 4A)
      - 2. AMERICAN NEWSPAPER PUBLISHERS ASSOCIATION LADIES--AT WORLD'S FAIR, APRIL 23 (Box 4A)
      - 3. BABYLON HIGH SCHOOL, BABYLON, L. I.--REMARKS ON CITIZENSHIP, APRIL 1 (Box 4A)
      - 4. BLACK, EUGENE--LUNCHEON IN HONOR OF--AT WALDORF-ASTORIA, JANUARY 16 (Box 4A)
      - 5. BOY SCOUT LUNCH-O-REE, WALDORF-ASTORIA, APRIL 17 (Box 4A)
      - 6. CONSULTING ENGINEERS, AMERICAN INSTITUTE OF--AWARD OF MERIT--HOTEL AMERICANA, OCTOBER 29 (Box 4A)
      - 7. DIRECTORS' MEETING--WORLD'S FAIR, JANUARY 24 (Box 4A)
      - 8. DIRECTORS' MEETING--WORLD'S FAIR, APRIL 22 (Box 4A)
      - 9. DIRECTORS' MEETING--WORLD'S FAIR, SEPTEMBER 26 (Box 4A)
      - 10. DOUGLASTON PARK GOLF COURSE, DEDICATION OF--BOROUGH OF QUEENS, APRIL 26 (Box 4A)
      - 11. EQUITABLE LIFE ASSURANCE SOCIETY PAVILION AT WORLD'S FAIR--ANNOUNCEMENT OF, JULY 30 (Box 4A)
      - 12. FIFTH AVENUE ASSOCIATION'S HONOR AWARD--SALUTE TO THE WORLD'S FAIR LUNCHEON, WALDORF-ASTORIA--"THE FAIR AND FIFTH AVENUE", OCTOBER 24 (Box 4A)
      - 13. FOREIGN CONSULS, SOCIETY OF--LUNCHEON AT PLAZA HOTEL, FEBRUARY 15 (Box 4A)
      - 14. GETTYSBURG ADDRESS, LUNCHEON IN CELEBRATION OF THE CENTENNIAL OF--SPRINGFIELD, ILLINOIS, NOVEMBER 19 (Box 4A)
      - 15. GOLDBERG, RUBE (80TH BIRTHDAY)--NATIONAL CARTOONIST SOCIETY'S LUNCHEON - WALDORF-ASTORIA, JUNE 6 (Box 4A)
      - 16. GOOD SAMARITAN BALL FOR THE BENEFIT OF GOOD SAMAITAN HOSPITAL - BAY SHORE, L. I., AUGUST 24 (Box 4A)
      - 17. HELIPORT AND EXHIBIT BUILDING, PORT OF NEW YORK AUTHORITY - OPENING OF - WORLD'S FAIR, OCTOBER 16 (Box 4A)
      - 18. HORTICULTURAL BUILDING OF QUEENS BOTANICAL SOCIETY, DEDICATION OF - KISSENA CORRIDOR PARK, OCTOBER 19 (Box 4A)
      - 19. JAPANESE PAVILION, GROUNDBREAKING AT FAIR, APRIL 15 (Box 4A)
      - 20. MARINE PARK, OPENING OF THE FIRST GOLF COURSE AT BROOKLYN, AUGUST 27 (Box 4A)
      - 21. MARINE THEATER, JONES BEACH - OPENING OF "AROUND THE WORLD IN EIGHTY DAYS", JUNE 22 (Box 4A)
      - 22. MARYLAND NORTHEASTERN EXPRESSWAY AND THE DELEWARE TURNPIKE, DEDICATION OF - MARYLAND-DELWARE LINE, NOVEMBER 14; AND MARYLAND NORTHEASTERN EXPRESSWAY AND THE DELEWARE TURNPIKE - REMARKS AT LUNCHEON - ABERDEEN, MARYLAND (Box 4A)
      - 23. NASSAU COMMUNITY COLLEGE CAMPUS, DEDICATION OF--MITCHEL FIELD, FEBRUARY 2 (Box 4A)
      - 24. NEW YORK STATE UTILITIES EXECUTIVE CONFERENCE - WALDORF-ASTORIA, SEPTEMBER 24 (Box 4A)
      - 25. PARK ASSOCIATION OF NEW YORK CITY, ANNUAL AWARD OF--LUNCHEON AT TAVERN-ON-THE-GREEN, MAY 2 (Box 4A)
      - 26. POWER VISTA, DEDICATION OF--ROBERT MOSES NIAGARA POWER PLANT, JULY 19 (Box 4A)
      - 27. PRESS BUILDING, DEDICATION OF--FLUSHING MEADOW, MAY 4 (Box 4A)
      - 28. PRESS CONFERENCE (FIRST) ON FAIR PROGRESS, PRESS BUILDING--WORLD'S FAIR, JUNE 27 (Box 4A)
      - 29. RADIO-NEWSREEL-TELEVISION WORKING PRESS ASSOCIATION, ANNUAL DINNER OF--HOTEL AMERICANA, APRIL 22 (Box 4A)
      - 30. ROBERT MOSES STATE PARK, DEDICATION OF--MASSENA, SEPTEMBER 17 (Box 4A)
      - 31. ST. GEORGE ASSOCIATION--12TH ANNUAL COMMUNION BREAKFAST--TOP OF FAIR--"GOD AND COUNTRY AWARD", DECEMBER 8 (Box 4A)
      - 32. ST. LAWRENCE VALLEY ASSOCIATION, TESTIMONIAL DINNER--SCHINE INN, MASSENA, SEPTEMBER 16 (Box 4A)
      - 33. SILURIANS, SOCIETY OF THE--ANNUAL FALL DINNER, GRAND STREET BOYS' CLUB--NEW YORK CITY, NOVEMBER 18 (Box 4A)
      - 34. VATICAN PAVILION--LUNCHEON FOR CARDINAL SPELLMAN AND OTHER PRIESTS ON--WORLD'S FAIR, APRIL 16 (Box 4A)
      - 35. VERRAZANO-NARROWS BRIDGE--CABLE SPINNING CEREMONY, MARCH 7 (Box 4A)
      - 36. YALE UNIVERSITY, SCHOOL OF ART AND ARCHITECTURE--"THE ANATOMY OF A FAIR", MARCH 13 (Box 4A)
    - ARTICLES BY ROBERT MOSES: 1963
      - FLATBUSH CHAMBER OF COMMERCE MAGAZINE - "COMMON GROUND", MARCH (Box 4A)
      - HERALD TRIBUNE - "FLUSHING MEADOW, UP FROM ASHES" - (REPRINT OF MAY 22, 1949), NOVEMBER (Box 4A)
      - LONG ISLAND PRESS - "MOSES VIEWS ROCHDALE, DECEMBER 1 (Box 4A)
      - NEW YORK DAILY MIRROR - "GEORGE E. SOKOLSKY: NEWSPAPERMAN", APRIL 3 (Box 4A)
      - ROCKAWAY REVIEW - "ARTERIAL GROWTH AIDS THE ROCKAWAYS", JUNE/JULY (Box 4A)
      - STATEN ISLAND ADVANCE - "YOU CAN WATCH, OR CAN DO", APRIL 27 (Box 4A)
  - 1964: 1st volume
    Scope and Contents
    The materials are listed in the order bound within the volume. Researchers should note that the contents list at the beginning of the volume list the Articles by Robert Moses first, but the articles of Moses are in fact bound after the speeches.
    - SPEECHES BY ROBERT MOSES--1964:
      - 1. AMALGAMATED CLOTHING WORKERS OF AMERICA AFL-CIO FIFTIETH ANNIVERSARY CONVENTION, SINGER BOWL, 5/9 (Box 5)
      - 2. ART-IN-JEWELS--OPENING OF OWEN CHEATHAM FOUNDATION COLLECTION, PAVILION OF SPAIN, 6/26 (Box 5)
      - 3. AVENUE OF THE AMERICAS ASSOCIATION OUTSTANDING ACHIEVEMENT AWARD, 6/3 (Box 5)
      - 4. BABYLON, LONG ISLAND'S ROBERT MOSES DAY AT FAIR, 6/12 (Box 5)
      - 5. BALTIMORE SYMPHONY ORCHESTRA--RECEPTION IN MARYLAND PAVILION, 8/4 (Box 5)
      - 6. BEAVER ISLAND GOLF COURSE DEDICATION, GRAND ISLAND, N. Y., 7/30 (Box 5)
      - 7. BELGIAN VILLAGE OPENING, 8/3 (Box 5)
      - 8. BOY SCOUTS OF AMERICA FIFTY-FOURTH NATIONAL COUNCIL ANNUAL MEETING, CLEVELAND, OHIO, 5/22 (Box 5)
      - 9. BOY SCOUT FUND DRIVE LAUNCHING, STONY BROOK, L. I., 11/24 (Box 5)
      - 10. CHURCH OF JESUS CHRIST OF LATTER DAY SAINTS--STATEMENT, 6/9 (Box 5)
      - 11. CONSOLIDATED EDISON ESSAY CONTEST PRIZE AWARDING, TERRACE CLUB, 11/15 (Box 5)
      - 12. DIRECTORS AND MEMBERS JOINT ANNUAL MEETING, TOP OF FAIR, 1/22 (Box 5)
      - 13. DIRECTORS MEETING, BETTER LIVING PAVILION, 6/22 (Box 5)
      - 14. FLUSHING ROTARY CLUB AWARD, HAWAIIAN PAVILION, 8/27 (Box 5)
      - 15. FORD MOTOR COMPANY EXHIBIT PRESS PREVIEW, 4/12 (Box 5)
      - 16. GENERAL MOTORS FUTURAMA EXHIBIT--TRIBUTE, 4/8 (Box 5)
      - 17. HAAS, DR. SIDNEY--FUNERAL SERVICES, 12/3 (Box 5)
      - 18. HALL OF SCIENCE OPENING CEREMONIES, 6/15 (Box 5)
      - 19. ILLINOIS PAVILION PREVIEW, LINCOLN THEATRE, 4/20 (Box 5)
      - 20. IBM DAY AT THE FAIR, 7/8 (Box 5)
      - 21. LaFARGE, FATHER JOHN, MEMORIAL AWARD DINNER, 6/10 (Box 5)
      - 22. LaGUARDIA, FIORELLO--DEDICATION OF SCULPTURE, LaGUARDIA AIRPORT, 12/2 (Box 5)
      - 23. LIBERTY HYDE BAILEY MEDAL--AMERICAN HORTICULTURAL SOCIETY, INDONESIAN THEATRE RESTAURANT, 9/30 (Box 5)
      - 24. MANHATTAN EYE, EAR AND THROAT HOSPITAL, FLUSHING MEADOW, 4/5 (Box 5)
      - 25. MANISCALCO, ALBERT V.--DINNER AT TAVERN-ON-THE-GREEN, STATEN ISLAND, 10/2 (Box 5)
      - 26. METROPOLITAN MUSEUM OF ART DINNER CELEBRATING OPENING OF FAIR FAIR, 4/14 (Box 5)
      - 27. MOSES, ROBERT--DEDICATION OF STATE PARKWAY AND RELATED FACILITIES ON NIAGARA FRONTIER, INCLUDING REMARKS OF JAMES A. FITZPATRICK, 7/30 (Box 5)
      - 28. MOSES, ROBERT--STATE PARK AND FIRE ISLAND INLET BRIDGE OPENING, 6/13 (Box 5)
      - 29. MARTIN MARIETTA SPACE EXHIBIT DEDICATION, HALL OF SCIENCE, FLUSHING MEADOW, 9/9 (Box 5)
      - 30. NATAL DAY, 12/18 (Box 5)
      - 31. NATIONAL ASSOCIATION OF SECRETARIES OF STATE, FLUSHING MEADOW, 7/2 (Box 5)
      - 32. NATIONAL HIGHWAY USERS, FLUSHING MEADOW, 5/8 (Box 5)
      - 33. NATIONAL PUBLIC WORKS WEEK DINNER, ATLANTIC CITY, N. J., 10/4 (Box 5)
      - 34. NEWSMAKER LUNCHEON, WALDORF ASTORIA, 4/13 (Box 5)